<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>developer on The Work Item</title>
    <link>https://theworkitem.com/tags/developer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in developer on The Work Item</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://theworkitem.com/tags/developer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E13 - Interview with Amanda Silver</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-amanda-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-amanda-silver/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item we interview Amanda Silver, Corporate Vice President, Developer Division at Microsoft. We discuss the process of building great developer tools, the human element in product design, and career advice for the long run.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Amanda on Twitter:
 https://twitter.com/amandaksilver  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E11 - Interview with Eric Martel</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-eric-martel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-eric-martel/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back after a week-long hiatus with an interview. This time, we chat with Eric Martel, Director of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning at Eidos-Montréal. We re-visit some of the gream games of the past, talk about console development considerations for modern games, and dig into how artificial intelligence and machine learning are going to revolutionize the engineering process.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E10 - Interview with Sara Chipps</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-sara-chipps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-sara-chipps/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Sara Chipps, Director of Public Q&amp;amp;A at Stack Overflow. Sara is also the founder of JewelBots, a company that provides electronic building kits for young inventors.
We chat with Sara about community feedback, engineering management career tracks, and building tools for STEM inclusivity.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Sara on the following sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E09 - Interview with Philipp Cannons</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-philipp-cannons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-philipp-cannons/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Philipp Cannons, CEO and founder of PMFIT.AI - a startup that aims to accelerate product success. Philipp talks about his experience starting a business from scratch and building a deep understanding of large organizations.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Philipp on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E08 - Interview with Charmaine Lee</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-charmaine-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-charmaine-lee/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Charmaine Lee, product manager intern at Microsoft, and a friend of the show. Charmaine talks about her experiences breaking into tech, building projects for fun, and being engaged in local tech scenes.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Charmaine on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E07 - Interview with Dan Fernandez</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-dan-fernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-dan-fernandez/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Dan Fernandez, VP of Product for Developer Services at Salesforce. Dan, a tech veteran, talks about product management, skill stacking, and building great developer experiences.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Dan on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  And if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about the archived blog post that we mentioned on the show where Dan is blonde, it&amp;rsquo;s still online!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E06 - Interview with Matt Swanson</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-matt-swanson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-matt-swanson/</guid>
      <description>Today, we had the honor of having an in-depth conversation with Matt Swanson, a software engineer at SEP, on engineering best practices, design systems, and managing complexity.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Matt on the following sites:
 Twitter GitHub Blog  And of course, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t wrap up this post without giving a shout-out to Matt&amp;rsquo;s project - Boring Rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E05 - Interview with Jin Yang</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-jin-yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-jin-yang/</guid>
      <description>A virtual fireside chat with Jin Yang, VP of design at CapitalOne. We discuss leadership, building great teams, and wrap up the show with food place recommendations.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Jin on social media:
 Twitter  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E04 - Interview with Clint Rutkas</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-clint-rutkas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-clint-rutkas/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, Courtny Cotten and Den Delimarsky chat with Clint Rutkas about PowerToys - a fantastic set of utilities for Windows power users.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Clint on the following Internet locations:
 Twitter GitHub  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E03 - Interview with April Speight</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-april-speight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-april-speight/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, Courtny Cotten and Den Delimarsky chat with April Speight, Senior Developer Advocate at Microsoft, about social media, writing Python books for kids and more.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find April on the following Internet locations:
 Twitter Twitch YouTube Her blog GitHub  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E02 - Career Starts</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/career-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/career-starts/</guid>
      <description>What is it like to start as a designer or a product manager? In this episode, Courtny and Den talk about their own journey in the tech industry, from the very early days!
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E01 - Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/remote-work/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work away from a tall office building in a large metropolis? Courtny and Den dive into this topic and more!
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>