<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>brand on The Work Item Podcast</title>
    <link>https://theworkitem.com/tags/brand/</link>
    <description>Recent content in brand on The Work Item Podcast</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://theworkitem.com/tags/brand/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>#25 - How to build a career in design and pitch Gary Vee, with Jack Zerby</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/how-to-build-design-career-jack-zerby/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/how-to-build-design-career-jack-zerby/</guid>
      <description>Jack Zerby is not your typical designer. His experience producing music, working at Pentagram and Frog, building startups, pitching to Gary Vee, and now - building tools for creators at Gumroad, puts him square in the middle of a very uncommon career path.
In this episode, I chat with Jack to learn more about what motivated him to grow his career, how to break into design, how to make the transition from a big company to a startup, and what does it mean to build compelling narratives in deck format.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S02E05 - Building Communities with Jess Lee</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/building-communities-with-jess-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/building-communities-with-jess-lee/</guid>
      <description>Jess Lee is the co-founder of dev.to - a developer community that emphasizes the importance of a friendly approach to guiding folks through the tumultuous waters of software development.
In this episode, we chat about Jess&amp;rsquo; career, the journey to founding Forem - the open-source platform powering large communities, and her experience building successful distributed teams.
The Show    You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Jess on the following sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S02E04 - From Servers, Phones, and Voice Assistants to Space with Charlie Kindel</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/going-to-space-with-charlie-kindel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/going-to-space-with-charlie-kindel/</guid>
      <description>Charlie Kindel is a tech industry veteran who helped bootstrap, grow, and manage teams that built home servers, phones, voice assistances, home automation software, and hopefully soon - space technologies.
In this episode, we dive a bit deeper into Charlie&amp;rsquo;s approach to product ideation and design, discuss the importance of having a principled organization, and ask questions about his most recent adventure around space.
The Show    You can also listen to the audio directly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S02E03 - Paige Bailey on Building a Career In Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-paige-bailey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-paige-bailey/</guid>
      <description>Paige Bailey is one of the few Artificial Intelligence (AI) and Machine Learning (ML) experts who is able to convey complex technical topics in an easy-to-understand and relatable language. Her Twitter feed is full of AI/ML paper recommendations, open source projects, and insights about the ever-evolving tech space.
What was her journey like to a career in a very complex domain? What does it mean to build an inclusive AI? This week, we sit down with Paige to learn from her experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S02E02 - Mayuko Inoue on Building a Content Creator Career Path</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-mayuko-inoue/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-mayuko-inoue/</guid>
      <description>Mayuko Inoue made a bold step by defying the stereotypical career path of a software engineer, and became a full-time content creator. Her videos on YouTube answer some of the more salient questions that are almost never covered in your typical coding tutorials and overviews.
What was behind this career decision and what were the lessons learned? How do you build a healthy community, and develop a good work-life balance? We talk to Mayuko about her personal take on the unique trajectory she&amp;rsquo;s carving, as well as the lessons learned along the way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S02E01 - Scott Hanselman on Intentionality</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-scott-hanselman/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-scott-hanselman/</guid>
      <description>Our first episode of the year is with the one and only Scott Hanselman. We tried to come up with a catchy title, but the entire episode could be summarized in one word - intentionality.
We discuss Scott&amp;rsquo;s foray into TikTok, building your own definition of success, and fostering strong relationships with people around you.
The Show    You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Scott on the following sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E19 - Wrap Up Episode For 2020</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/wrap-up-episode-for-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/wrap-up-episode-for-2020/</guid>
      <description>Den and Courtny reflect on the year we just went through, and discuss our plans for 2021. There is a lot to be thankful for, and we had quite a year kickstarting a new podcast from scratch.
This also happens to be the last episode of our Season 1.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 We&amp;rsquo;re excited to see in 2021, with more interviews and interesting topics!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E18 - Megan Risdal on Building a Career at the Intersection of Data Science and Product Management</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-megan-risdal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-megan-risdal/</guid>
      <description>Right before the Thanksgiving break, we are releasing a fresh new episode with Megan Risdal, Product Lead at Kaggle. Megan took the multi-talented route to the career she has today, and enjoys every bit of it.
In this episode, we talk about the importance of being a multi-dimensional professional in a product role, finding the best ways to collect customer feedback, and building communities at scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E17 - Christos Matskas on Going From Consulting to Corporate and Building Identity Tools</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-christos-matskas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-christos-matskas/</guid>
      <description>In a surprising twist, this week we chat with Christos Matskas about on topics - transitioning from consulting life to a corporate life, as well as about building identity tools and services in the cloud.
Christos goes in depth about the aspects of his previous jobs that brought him to a fulfilling career at Microsoft, and then gives us a crash course on why it&amp;rsquo;s important to use professionally-managed identity services in your applications instead of rolling your own solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E16 - Bill Kenney on Building Brands That Last</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-bill-kenney/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-bill-kenney/</guid>
      <description>This weekend, we go outdoors with Bill Kenney, co-founder of Focus Lab, a branding agency that is entirely remote. We talk to Bill about the importance of a good brand and what distinguishes professionals from amateurs in the field.
This also happens to be the the first time we chat to a person that knows the ins and outs of branding, so lessons learned all around.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E15 - Tarun Gangwani on Innovation, Navigating Product Decisions, and Building Growth Engines</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-tarun-gangwani/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-tarun-gangwani/</guid>
      <description>We sit down to chat with Tarun Gangwani, Senior Product Manager at Sanity.io. Tarun is a seasoned PM with tons of expertise to share about the product management domain.
With previous experience at Twitch, where he oversaw the entire lifecycle of a developer using extensions and data services to create engaging and personalized viewing and streaming experiences, Tarun is talking about lessons learned, differences between startup and large company environments, along with the ways in which product managers can broaden the understanding of their products and customer needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E14 - Interview with Richard Lander</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-richard-lander/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-richard-lander/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item we interview Richard Lander, Principal Program Manager on the .NET team at Microsoft. Richard does a deep dive on communication, being a generalist vs. specialist, and growing one&amp;rsquo;s career.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Richard on Twitter:
 https://twitter.com/runfaster2000  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E13 - Interview with Amanda Silver</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-amanda-silver/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-amanda-silver/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item we interview Amanda Silver, Corporate Vice President, Developer Division at Microsoft. We discuss the process of building great developer tools, the human element in product design, and career advice for the long run.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Amanda on Twitter:
 https://twitter.com/amandaksilver  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E12 - Interview with Christina Weng</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-christina-weng/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-christina-weng/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item we interview Christina Weng, product designer at Facebook, about building a career in user experience design from scratch.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Christina on her blog:
 https://christinaweng.com  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E11 - Interview with Eric Martel</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-eric-martel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-eric-martel/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;re back after a week-long hiatus with an interview. This time, we chat with Eric Martel, Director of Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning at Eidos-Montréal. We re-visit some of the gream games of the past, talk about console development considerations for modern games, and dig into how artificial intelligence and machine learning are going to revolutionize the engineering process.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E10 - Interview with Sara Chipps</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-sara-chipps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-sara-chipps/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Sara Chipps, Director of Public Q&amp;amp;A at Stack Overflow. Sara is also the founder of JewelBots, a company that provides electronic building kits for young inventors.
We chat with Sara about community feedback, engineering management career tracks, and building tools for STEM inclusivity.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Sara on the following sites:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E09 - Interview with Philipp Cannons</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-philipp-cannons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-philipp-cannons/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Philipp Cannons, CEO and founder of PMFIT.AI - a startup that aims to accelerate product success. Philipp talks about his experience starting a business from scratch and building a deep understanding of large organizations.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Philipp on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E08 - Interview with Charmaine Lee</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-charmaine-lee/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-charmaine-lee/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Charmaine Lee, product manager intern at Microsoft, and a friend of the show. Charmaine talks about her experiences breaking into tech, building projects for fun, and being engaged in local tech scenes.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Charmaine on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E07 - Interview with Dan Fernandez</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-dan-fernandez/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-dan-fernandez/</guid>
      <description>In this episode of The Work Item, we interview Dan Fernandez, VP of Product for Developer Services at Salesforce. Dan, a tech veteran, talks about product management, skill stacking, and building great developer experiences.
   You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Dan on the following sites:
 Twitter Blog  And if you&amp;rsquo;re curious about the archived blog post that we mentioned on the show where Dan is blonde, it&amp;rsquo;s still online!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E06 - Interview with Matt Swanson</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-matt-swanson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-matt-swanson/</guid>
      <description>Today, we had the honor of having an in-depth conversation with Matt Swanson, a software engineer at SEP, on engineering best practices, design systems, and managing complexity.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Matt on the following sites:
 Twitter GitHub Blog  And of course, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t wrap up this post without giving a shout-out to Matt&amp;rsquo;s project - Boring Rails.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E05 - Interview with Jin Yang</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-jin-yang/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-with-jin-yang/</guid>
      <description>A virtual fireside chat with Jin Yang, VP of design at CapitalOne. We discuss leadership, building great teams, and wrap up the show with food place recommendations.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Jin on social media:
 Twitter  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E04 - Interview with Clint Rutkas</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-clint-rutkas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-clint-rutkas/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, Courtny Cotten and Den Delimarsky chat with Clint Rutkas about PowerToys - a fantastic set of utilities for Windows power users.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find Clint on the following Internet locations:
 Twitter GitHub  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E03 - Interview with April Speight</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-april-speight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/interview-april-speight/</guid>
      <description>In this episode, Courtny Cotten and Den Delimarsky chat with April Speight, Senior Developer Advocate at Microsoft, about social media, writing Python books for kids and more.
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 You can find April on the following Internet locations:
 Twitter Twitch YouTube Her blog GitHub  Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts, Google Play Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E02 - Career Starts</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/career-starts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/career-starts/</guid>
      <description>What is it like to start as a designer or a product manager? In this episode, Courtny and Den talk about their own journey in the tech industry, from the very early days!
   
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts and Spotify.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E01 - Remote Work</title>
      <link>https://theworkitem.com/blog/remote-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theworkitem.com/blog/remote-work/</guid>
      <description>Have you ever wondered what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work away from a tall office building in a large metropolis? Courtny and Den dive into this topic and more in the inaugural episode of The Work Item podcast!
The Show    
You can also listen to the audio directly:
 Check this episode out on Apple Podcasts and Spotify.
Transcript </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>